Himanshu Soni

Full Stack Developer

\$\&\ +91-8871778862\$

himanshua790@gmail.com

in @himanshuu-soni

© @himanshua790

@code-08

fullstacktony.in

Summary

Entrepreneurial spirit and a passion for learning and growth. I am able to work independently with a growth mindset and excellent problem-solving skills. A collaborative team player with strong communication and good management skills. Experienced in fast-paced startup environments.

Work Experience

HandajiTech

Fullstack Developer Contract

11/2023 - 02/2024

- Led Frontend development for the Greytt platform, a remote gig-finding platform for experienced individuals aged 50+.
- Built the entire application from scratch, including version 1.0, with a focus on frontend work, API integration, and influencing business logic and database schema.
- Developed UI for the full platform, featuring company and user dashboards, chat screen, AI job creation, search filters, and personalized talent and company searches.
- Created modular components from scratch to ensure UI consistency and optimized performance.
- Collaboratively contributed to logic building, UX/UI design, client communication, and leading client demos.
- Integrated Stripe for <u>Skaleit</u>, including audit logging using SQL Sequelize for storyboarding similar to Jira and Trello functionalities.
- Worked on Shftr, a job-related app built with React Native.
- Tech: React Query, Typescript, React Optimization, Tailwind CSS, React Form Hook, React Native, Stripe Integration, Integrating API, SQL Sequelize.

Fuel Growth (Integrations)

Software Developer Part-Time

08/2023 - 10/2023

- Provided seamless integration support for Shopify, Facebook, TikTok integration.
- Collaborated with the fuelgrowth at team to implement data-driven strategies for ecommerce optimization.

RoaDo

Software Developer Full-Time

01/2022 - 07/2023

- Developed geofencing feature with GPS for fleet tracking and notifications, improving fleet tracking accuracy by 20%.
- Built Dealer module to facilitate communication between industries.
- Restructured application to support multiple sources and destinations and added multilevel filters.
- Revamped the UI and functionality of the assignment module, resulting in a significant 62% improvement in user experience.
- Tech: MongoDB, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, Redis, AWS S3, Redux, PWA, Material UI.

Autowriter.ai (Product Description Generator)

Full-Stack Developer Self-Employed

05/2021 - 01/2022

- Developed Shopify application that generated product descriptions.
- Maintained and improved GPT-3 APIs for better results.
- Collaborated with the team to troubleshoot and debug issues.
- Tech: JavaScript, Redux, Next.js, Polaris, OAuth, Shopify App-Bridge, Express, GraphQL, RabbitMQ.

Python Developer Internship 01/2021 - 05/2021

- Developed a constrained vehicle routing solution that improved efficiency by 32% over manual routing.
- Established a data pipeline to validate customer addresses.
- Developed dashboards and reports to track key performance indicators.
- Tech: Google OR-Tools, Scripting, Python, SQL, Data Scraping, MS-Excel, Git, HTML, CSS.

Project

Rishihood University - Swami Vivekananda Chatbot

- Designed, developed, and deployed an innovative AI-powered platform, <u>vivekananda.ai</u>, to revolutionize book research and interaction.
- Leveraged modern technologies including Langchain, React.js, and Next.js to create a dynamic and user-friendly interface.
- Implemented an intelligent search system that provides contextually relevant answers from book content, resulting in enriched user interactions.
- Quantified impact: Increased user engagement by 40%.
- Media Coverage: LinkedIn, Twitter.

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communications Medi-Caps University, Indore Specialization in Computer Technologies. 2016 – 2020 CGPA: 7.48/10

Skills

Frontend Technologies

• Markup & Styling: HTML, CSS, Markdown, SASS/SCSS

• Scripting: JavaScript, TypeScript

• Frameworks: Next.js, React.js, Three.js, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI

• Code Quality: ESLint, Prettier

 \bullet Web Technologies: Web Components, Service Workers

• Testing: Puppeteer, Jest

Backend Technologies

• Core: Node.js, Python

Frameworks: Express, DjangoOthers: Bash, JWT, OAuth

• Testing & Debugging: Jest, Visual Studio

• Message Broker: RabbitMQ

Databases

• SQL: MySQL, PostgreSQL

NoSQL: MongoDBInMemory: Redis

Cloud Platforms

• AWS: Lambda, S3, API Gateway, EC2, Elastic IP

• Google Cloud Platform: OAuth2, Gmail API

Interests

Passionate about web development and design, ecommerce, and using augmented reality to create immersive shopping experiences. Also, deeply interested in building scalable applications with the aim of serving millions of users. My goal is to develop full-fledged, highly scalable applications that can meet the demands of a large user base.